Using Language Reading
Showing Our Feelings
Body language is one of the most powerful means of communication, often even more powerful
than spoken language.
People around the world show all kinds of feelings,
wishes and attitudes that they might never speak aloud.
It is possible to "read" others around us,
even if they do not intend for us to catch their unspoken communication.
Of course, body language can be misread,
but many gestures and actions are universal.
The most universal facial expression is,
of course, the smile – its function is to show happiness and put people at ease.
It does not always mean that we are truly happy,
however.
Smiles around the world can be false,
hiding other feelings like anger,
fear or worry.
There are unhappy smiles, such as when someone "loses face"
and smiles to hide it.
However, the general purpose of smiling is to show good feelings.
From the time we are babies, we show unhappiness or anger by frowning.
In most places around the world,
frowning and turning one's back to someone shows anger.
Making a fist and shaking it almost always means that someone is angry
and threatening another person.
There are many ways around the world to show agreement,
but nodding the head up and down is used for agreement,
almost worldwide.
Most people also understand that shaking the head from side to side means disagreement or refusal.
How about showing that I am bored?
Looking away from people or yawning will,
in most cases, make me appear to be uninterested.
However, if I turn toward and look at someone or something,
people from almost every culture will think that I am interested.
If I roll my eyes and turn my head away,
I most likely do not believe what I am hearing or do not like it.
Being respectful to people is subjective,
based on each culture, but in general it is probably not a good idea to give a hug to a boss or teacher.
In almost every culture, it is not usually good to stand too close to someone of a higher rank.
Standing at a little distance with open hands will show that I am willing to listen.
With so many cultural differences between people,
it is great to have some similarities in body language.
We can often be wrong about each other,
so it is an amazing thing that we understand each other as well as we do!